Guide to the Hal Lehrman papers, 1940-1970.
Lehrman, Hal papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hal Lehrman papers, 1940-1970.
6932
Hal. Lehrman
48 boxes.
Correspondence, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files and clippings relating to Hal Lehrman's career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Hal Lehrman graduated Phi Beta Kappa from Cornell University in 1932. He began his career as a reporter with the Associated Press in 1934, and went on to work at Newsweek, The Daily News, and The Herald Tribune, as well as doing freelance-writing and book reviewing for The New York Times, The New York Post, The Wall Street Journal and Newsday. He was also a contributor Life magazine, Commentary, Harper’s, and The Reader’s Digest. In 1957, Lehrman won the George Polk Award for Outstanding Foreign Reporting. He became a founding member of the Overseas Press Club in 1939, and was president of it from 1967 to 1970. After retiring, he continued his longtime, active membership with the Council on Foreign Relations of the Rockefeller Foundation. Lehrman passed away in 1988 of a heart attack.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection contains files and clippings pertaining to Lehrman's career. The first forty-two boxes contain newspaper clippings and articles related to certain aspects (political, economic, militaristic) of specific countries, both Eastern and Western. There is a strong focus on Israel, the Middle East, and “the West.” Most of these clippings are from the 1960s, though some are from before or after this period. Additionally, five more boxes contain documents and correspondences from Overseas Press Club, primarily from the 1960s when Lehrman was president of the club. There are a number of notable items, including documents produced by the Office of War Information, papers on Vietnam marked “confidential” from the Council on Foreign Relations, 28 photos of an Israeli family taken in 1956, a speech given by Charles De Gaulle in 1962, and a “War Atlas for Americans” book from 1944.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lehrman, Hal.; Council on Foreign Relations.; Overseas Press Club of America.; United States.Office of War Information.
Subjects:
Journalists--United States.
Places:
Vietnam--History--20th century.; Albania--History--20th century.; France--History--20th century.; Israel--History--20th century.; Israel
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Country Subject File Collection
  - Aden (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Afganistan (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Africa - Asia (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Africa - Background, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Africa - Political, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Africa - Biblio (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Africa - Biography (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa - Britain (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Africa- China (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Africa - Economy (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Africa - France (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Africa - Political, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Africa - Political, Through 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Africa - Portugal, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Africa - Soviet (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Africa - U.S. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Albania - Political (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Albania (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Albania - Background (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Albania - Economy, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Algeria - Africa (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Algeria - Background, Through 1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Algeria - Background, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Algeria - Background, 1956 and after (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Algeria - Asia (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Algeria - Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Algeria - Biography (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Algeria - Britain (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Algeria - China (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Algeria - Congo (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Algeria - Cuba (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Algeria - Economy, Through 1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Algeria - Economy, 1960 and after (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Algeria - Egypt (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Algeria - "Foreign C." (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Algeria - Political, 1965 and after (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Algeria - France, Before July 1962 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Algeria - Germany (West) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Algeria - Israel (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Algeria - Middle East (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Algeria - Morocco (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Algeria - France, After July 1962 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Algeria - Background - Political, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Algeria - C - Political, September 1962 to December 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Algeria - C - Political, July 1962 to August 1962 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Algeria - C - Political, April 1962 to June 1962 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Algeria - C - Political, March 1962 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Algeria - C - Political, January 1962 to February 1962 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Algeria - Political, July 1961 to December 1961 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Algeria - Political, January 1961 to July 1961 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Algeria - Political, July 1960 to December 1960 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Algeria - Political, January 1960 to June 1960 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Algeria - C - Political, July 1959 to December 1959 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Algeria - C - Political, January 1959 to June 1959 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Algeria - C - Political, July 1958 to December 1958 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Algeria - Political, January 1958 to June 1958 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Algeria - C - Political, July 1957 to December 1957 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Algeria - C - Political, January 1957 to June 1957 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Algeria - C - Political, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Algeria - Political, October 1955 to December 1955 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Algeria - C - Political, January 1955 to September 1955 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Algeria - C - Political, Up to 1954 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Algeria - Portugal (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Algeria - Sahara (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Algeria - Soviet Union (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Algria - Tunisia (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Algeria - U.S. (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Algeria - Yugoslavia (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Angola (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Arab League - Background (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Arab League - C - Political (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Asia (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Austria (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Algiers - Correspondences, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Bahamas (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Bulgaria - Background (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Bulgaria - Political, 1944-1952 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Burundi (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Cambodia (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Cameroun (now Cameroon) (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Caribbean (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Castles (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Cayman Islands (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Central African Republic (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Ceylon (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - China - Background - P.+ E. (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - China - Asia (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - China - Latin (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - China - US: Political (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Czechoslovakia - Political, 1940-1952 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Congo - Africa (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Congo - Biography (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Congo - Economy - C (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Congo - Egypt (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Congo - France (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Congo - Kenya (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Congo - Nigeria (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Congo - Political (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Congo - South Africa (Union) (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Congo - Soviet Union (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Costa Rica (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Cuba (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Czechoslovakia - Background and Personal (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Czechoslovakia - Economy, 1940-1951 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Dahomey (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Dominican Republic - Background (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Dominican Republic - Economy (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Dominican Republic - Haiti (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Dominican Republic - Political, 1966 and after (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Dominican Republic - Political, July 1965 to December 1965 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Dominican Republic - Political, January 1965 to June 1965 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Dominican Republic - Chrond - Political, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Dominican Republic - U.S.A. (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Egypt - Africa - Asia (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Egypt - Armed Forces (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Egypt - Background (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Egypt - Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Egypt - Biography (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Egypt - Economy (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Egypt - Economy, 1945-1955 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Egypt - Europe (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Egypt - Foreign, After 1959 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Egypt - Foreign, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Egypt - Foreign, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Egypt - Germany (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Egypt - Gulf (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Egypt - Iran (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Egypt - Iraq (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Egypt - Jordan (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Egypt - Lebanon (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Egypt - Libya (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Egypt - Middle East (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Egypt - Military (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Egypt - North Africa - B. (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Egypt - Palestine (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Egypt - Political (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Egypt - Religion (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Egypt - Saudi Arabia (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Egypt - Soviet (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Egypt - Sudan (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Egypt - Syria (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Egypt - Tunisia (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Egypt - Turkey (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Egypt - U.S. Political (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Egypt - U.S. - B + C - Economy (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Egypt - Yemen (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - France - Algeria, After July 1962 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - France - Algeria, Before July 1962 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - France - Asia (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - France - Background (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - France - Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - France - Biography (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - France - China, After January 1964 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - France - Colonial (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - France - Economical (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - France - Foreign, After 1963 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - France - Foreign, Through 1962 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - France - Germany, Pre 1964 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - France - West Germany, 1964 and after (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - France - Indo-China (Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos), 1964 and after (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - France - Latin America, 1964 and after (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - France - Libya (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - France - Middle East (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - France - Military (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - France - Morocco - Economy (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - France - Morocco - Political (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - France - North Africa (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - France - Political, January 1968 and after (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - France - C - Political, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - France - Soviet, 1964 and after (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - France - Soustelle (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - France - Political, Through 1963 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - France - U.S., 1964 and after (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - France - "Sous - MS" (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - France - Tunisia (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - France - U.S., Pre 1964 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - France - West - Economy (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - France - West - Military (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - France - West - Political (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Ghana (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Gulf States - Background (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - Gulf States - Great Britain (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Gulf States - Middle East (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - Gulf States - Political and Economical (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - Haiti - Background (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Haiti - Dominican Republic (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Haiti - C - Economy (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - Haiti - C - Political (Box 9, Folder 189)
  - Hungary (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - Hungary - Background (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - Hungary - Unfiled, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - Hungary - Economy, 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Hungary - Political, 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - Indonesia (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - Iran - Background, Bibliography, and Biography (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Iran - Economy (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - Iran - Foreign (Box 10, Folder 198)
  - Iran - Iraq (Box 10, Folder 199)
  - Iran - Lebanon (Box 10, Folder 200)
  - Iran - Political (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - Iran - Soviet (Box 10, Folder 202)
  - Iran - U.S. (Box 10, Folder 203)
  - Iraq - Background, Biography, Bibliography, etc. (Box 10, Folder 204)
  - Iraq - Economy (Box 10, Folder 205)
  - Iraq - Egypt (Box 10, Folder 206)
  - Iraq - Foreign (Box 10, Folder 207)
  - Iraq - Kurds (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - Iraq - Political (Box 10, Folder 209)
  - Iraq - Soviet (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - Iraq - Syria (Box 10, Folder 211)
  - Iraq - West (Box 10, Folder 212)
  - Israel - Afro/Asia (Box 10, Folder 213)
  - Israel - American Judaism, Until 1960 (Box 10, Folder 214)
  - Israel - Americans In... (Box 10, Folder 215)
  - Israel - Arab Boycott, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 216)
  - Israel - American Judaism, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 217)
  - Israel - Arab Boycott (Box 11, Folder 218)
  - Israel - Arab League (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - Israel - Arabs (Box 11, Folder 220)
  - Israel - Arabs In... - Background (Box 11, Folder 221)
  - Israel - Arabs In... - Economy (Box 11, Folder 222)
  - Israel - Arabs In... - Political (Box 11, Folder 223)
  - Israel - Army (Box 11, Folder 224)
  - Israel - Art (Box 11, Folder 225)
  - Israel - BKNGO, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 226)
  - Israel - Brochures and Maps (Box 12, Folder 227)
  - Israel - Background, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 228)
  - Israel - Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 229)
  - Israel - Biography (Box 12, Folder 230)
  - Israel - Character (Box 12, Folder 231)
  - Israel - Development, 1963 and after (Box 12, Folder 232)
  - Israel - Development, Through 1962 (Box 12, Folder 233)
  - Israel - East Europe (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - Israel - Economy, 1966 and after (Box 13, Folder 235)
  - Israel - Economy, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 236)
  - Israel - Economy, July 1964 to December 1964 (Box 13, Folder 237)
  - Israel - Economy, January 1964 to June 1964 (Box 13, Folder 238)
  - Israel - Economy, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 239)
  - Israel - Economy, July to December 1963 (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - Israel - Economy, January to June 1963 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - Israel - Economy, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Israel - Economy, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Israel - Economy, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - Israel - Economy, May 1959 to December 1959 (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Israel - Economy, January 1959 to April 1959 (Box 14, Folder 246)
  - Israel - Economy, July 1958 to December 1958 (Box 14, Folder 247)
  - Israel - Economy, January 1958 to June 1958 (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - Israel - Economy, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Israel - Economy, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 250)
  - Israel - Economy, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 251)
  - Israel - Economy, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 252)
  - Israel - Economy, 1952-1953 (Box 15, Folder 253)
  - Israel - Economy, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 254)
  - Israel - Economy, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - Israel - Economy, Through 1949 (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Israel - Education, 1962 and after (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Israel - Education, Through 1961 (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Israel - Egypt, 1959 and after (Box 16, Folder 259)
  - Israel - Egypt, 1957 to 1968 (Box 16, Folder 260)
  - Israel - Egypt, Through 1956 (Box 16, Folder 261)
  - Israel - Finance (Box 16, Folder 262)
  - Israel - Foreign, 1960 and after (Box 16, Folder 263)
  - Israel - Foreign, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 264)
  - Israel - Foreign, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 265)
  - Israel - Foreign, May 1956 to December 1956 (Box 17, Folder 266)
  - Israel - Foreign, January 1956 to April 1956 (Box 17, Folder 267)
  - Israel - Foreign, June 1955 to December 1955 (Box 17, Folder 268)
  - Israel - Foreign, January 1955 to June 1955 (Box 17, Folder 269)
  - Israel - Foreign, To 1955 (Box 17, Folder 270)
  - Israel - France (Box 17, Folder 271)
  - Israel - Fund-Raising, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 272)
  - Israel - Fund-raising, To 1955 (Box 17, Folder 273)
  - Israel - Germany (Box 17, Folder 274)
  - Israel - Government, 1960 and after (Box 17, Folder 275)
  - Israel - Government, Through 1959 (Box 18, Folder 276)
  - Israel - Great Britain (Box 18, Folder 277)
  - Israel - Greece (Box 18, Folder 278)
  - Israel - Immigration, 1958 and after (Box 18, Folder 279)
  - Israel - Immigration/Emigration, Through 1957 (Box 18, Folder 280)
  - Israel - Iraq (Box 18, Folder 281)
  - Israel - Japan (Box 18, Folder 282)
  - Israel - Jordan (Box 18, Folder 283)
  - Israeli Kibbutzim (Box 18, Folder 284)
  - Israel - Labor, 1963 and after (Box 18, Folder 285)
  - Israel - Labor, Through 1962 (Box 18, Folder 286)
  - Israel - Latin America (Box 18, Folder 287)
  - Israel - Lebanon (Box 19, Folder 288)
  - Israel - Middle East, July 1969 and after (Box 19, Folder 289)
  - Israel - Middle East, 1965 to June 1969 (Box 19, Folder 290)
  - Israel - Middle East, 1958-1964 (Box 19, Folder 291)
  - Israel - Middle East, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 292)
  - Israel - Military (Box 19, Folder 293)
  - Israel - Morocco (Box 19, Folder 294)
  - Israel - Oriental Jewry, 1952 and after (Box 19, Folder 295)
  - Israel - Oriental Jewry, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 296)
  - Israel - Oriental Jewry, Through 1950 (Box 19, Folder 297)
  - Israel - Political, 1965 and after (Box 19, Folder 298)
  - Israel - Political, September 1964 to December 1964 (Box 20, Folder 299)
  - Israel - Political, January 1964 to August 1964 (Box 20, Folder 300)
  - Israel - Political, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 301)
  - Israel - Political, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 302)
  - Israel - Political, July 1961 to December 1961 (Box 20, Folder 303)
  - Israel - Political, January 1961 to June 1961 (Box 20, Folder 304)
  - Israel - Political, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 305)
  - Israel - Political, July 1959 to December 1959 (Box 20, Folder 306)
  - Israel - Political, January 1959 to June 1959 (Box 20, Folder 307)
  - Israel - Political, 1957-1958 (Box 20, Folder 308)
  - Israel - Political, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 309)
  - Israel - Political, 1953-1954 (Box 20, Folder 310)
  - Israel - Political, 1950-1952 (Box 20, Folder 311)
  - Israel - Political, September 1949 to December 1949 (Box 20, Folder 312)
  - Israel - Political, January 1949 to August 1949 (Box 20, Folder 313)
  - Israel - Political, April 1948 to December 1948 (Box 21, Folder 314)
  - Israel - Political, January 1948 to March 1948 (Box 21, Folder 315)
  - Israel - Political, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 316)
  - Israel - Political, 1945-1946 (Box 21, Folder 317)
  - Israel - Political, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 318)
  - Israel - Refugees, 1963 and after (Box 21, Folder 319)
  - Israel - Refugees, To 1963 (Box 21, Folder 320)
  - Israel - Religious, 1968 and after (Box 21, Folder 321)
  - Israel - Religious, 1963 to 1967 (Box 21, Folder 322)
  - Not part of collection as of 2/17/11, presumed to not have been included in original donation (Box 21, Folder 323-332)
  - Israel - Religious, To 1962 (Box 21, Folder 333)
  - Israel - Saudi Arabia (Box 22, Folder 334)
  - Israel - Scandinavia (Box 22, Folder 335)
  - Israel - Soviet Union (Box 22, Folder 336)
  - Israel - Spain (Box 22, Folder 337)
  - Israel - U.N. (Box 22, Folder 338)
  - Israel - U.S. - Economy (Box 22, Folder 339)
  - Israel - U.S. - Politics, 1968 and after (Box 22, Folder 340)
  - Israel - U.S. - Politics, Through 1967 (Box 22, Folder 341)
  - Israel - Syria (Box 22, Folder 342)
  - Israel - Tunisia (Box 22, Folder 343)
  - Israel - Turkey (Box 22, Folder 344)
  - Israel - vatican City (Box 22, Folder 345)
  - Israel - World Jewry (Box 22, Folder 346)
  - Israel - Zionism, 1962 and after (Box 22, Folder 347)
  - Israel - Agriculture (Box 22, Folder 348)
  - Israel - Algeria (Box 22, Folder 349)
  - Israel - Zionism, Through 1961 (Box 23, Folder 350)
  - Ivory Coast (Box 23, Folder 351)
  - Not among collection as of 2/17/2011 (Box 23, Folder 352)
  - Jews - Algeria (Box 23, Folder 353)
  - Jews - Argentina (Box 23, Folder 354)
  - Jews - Austria (Box 23, Folder 355)
  - Jews - Bibliography - Biography (Box 23, Folder 356)
  - Jews - Britain (Box 23, Folder 357)
  - Jews - Balkaus (Box 23, Folder 358)
  - Jews - Canaoa (Box 23, Folder 359)
  - Jews - Czechoslovakia (Box 23, Folder 340 A)
  - Jews - Egypt (Box 23, Folder 341 A)
  - Jews - France (Box 23, Folder 342 A)
  - Jews - Germany, 1960 and after (Box 23, Folder 343 A)
  - Jews - Germany, 1952-1959 (Box 23, Folder 344 A)
  - Jews - Germany, 1946-1951 (Box 23, Folder 345 A)
  - Jews - Greece (Box 24, Folder 346 A)
  - Jews - Holland (Box 24, Folder 347 A)
  - Jews - Hungary (Box 24, Folder 348 A)
  - Jews - Iran (Box 24, Folder 349 A)
  - Jews - Iraq (Box 24, Folder 350 A)
  - Jews - Italy (Box 24, Folder 351 A)
  - Jews - Latin America (Box 24, Folder 352 A)
  - Jews - Lebanon (Box 24, Folder 353 A)
  - Jews - Libya (Box 24, Folder 354 A)
  - Jews - Middle East (Box 24, Folder 355 A)
  - Jews - Morocco (Box 24, Folder 356 A)
  - Jews - Morocoo (Box 24, Folder 357 A)
  - Jews - North Africa (Box 24, Folder 358 A)
  - Jews - Poland (Box 24, Folder 359 A)
  - Jews - Poland - Study (Box 24, Folder 360)
  - Jews - Poland (Box 24, Folder 361)
  - Jews - Romania, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 362)
  - Jews - Romania (Box 24, Folder 363)
  - Jews - Soviet (Box 24, Folder 364)
  - Jews - Soviet, 1970 and after (Box 25, Folder 365)
  - Jews - Soviet, 1965-1969 (Box 25, Folder 366)
  - Jews - Soviet, 1962-1964 (Box 25, Folder 367)
  - Jews - Russia, To 1962 (Box 25, Folder 368)
  - Jews - Spain (Box 25, Folder 369)
  - Jews - Switzerland (Box 25, Folder 370)
  - Jews - Syria (Box 25, Folder 371)
  - Jews - Tunisia (Box 25, Folder 372)
  - Jews - Turkey (Box 25, Folder 373)
  - Jews - Misc. Unions of Africa (Box 25, Folder 374)
  - Jews - U.S., After 1950 (Box 25, Folder 375)
  - Jews - U.S., Through 1950 (Box 25, Folder 376)
  - Jews - Vatican (Box 26, Folder 377)
  - Jews - Vatican (Box 26, Folder 378)
  - Jews - World (Box 26, Folder 379)
  - Jews - Zionism (Box 26, Folder 380)
  - Jews - Yugoslavia (Box 26, Folder 381)
  - Jordan - Background - Bibliography - Biography (Box 26, Folder 382)
  - Jordan - Economy (Box 26, Folder 383)
  - Jordan - Foreign (Box 26, Folder 384)
  - Jordan - Middle East (Box 26, Folder 385)
  - Jordan - Palestine (Box 26, Folder 386)
  - Jordan - Political (Box 26, Folder 387)
  - Jordan - U.S. (Box 26, Folder 388)
  - Kenya (Box 26, Folder 389)
  - Laos (Box 26, Folder 390)
  - Latin America (Box 26, Folder 391)
  - Lebanon - Background (Box 26, Folder 392)
  - Lebanon - Economy (Box 26, Folder 393)
  - Lebanon - Foreign (Box 26, Folder 394)
  - Lebanon - Middle East (Box 26, Folder 395)
  - Lebanon - Political (Box 26, Folder 396)
  - Lebanon - Syria (Box 26, Folder 397)
  - Liberia (Box 26, Folder 398)
  - Libya (Box 26, Folder 399)
  - Madagascar (Box 26, Folder 400)
  - Malawi (Box 26, Folder 401)
  - Malaysia (Box 26, Folder 402)
  - Malta (Box 26, Folder 403)
  - Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 404)
  - Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 405)
  - Mauritania (Box 27, Folder 406)
  - Misc. Mediterranean (Box 27, Folder 407)
  - Middle East - Background (Box 27, Folder 408)
  - Middle East - Bibliography (Box 27, Folder 409)
  - Middle East - Biography (Box 27, Folder 410)
  - Middle East - Britain (Box 27, Folder 411)
  - Middle East - China (Box 27, Folder 412)
  - Middle East - Economy (Box 27, Folder 413)
  - Middle East - Foreign (Box 27, Folder 414)
  - Middle East - Military (Box 27, Folder 415)
  - Middle East - France (Box 27, Folder 416)
  - Middle East - Germany (Box 27, Folder 417)
  - Middle East - Politics, 1965 and after (Box 27, Folder 418)
  - Middle East - Politics, To 1965 (Box 27, Folder 419)
  - Middle East - Soviet (Box 27, Folder 420)
  - Middle East - Tunisia (Box 28, Folder 421)
  - Middle East - Turkey (Box 28, Folder 422)
  - Middle East - U.N. (Box 28, Folder 423)
  - Middle East - U.S. (Box 28, Folder 424)
  - Morocco - Background (Box 28, Folder 425)
  - Morocco - Bibliography (Box 28, Folder 426)